Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. George Eversman Papers, 1973-1976 and undated RL.11141
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. George Eversman papers
1973-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11141
0.8 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. George Eversman was an executive with JWT, managing New York Advertising and the Detroit office before finishing his career with N. W. Ayer.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Born circa 1917. U.S. Marine Corps 1945: two tours, final rank of Colonel in Marine Reserves. BS Purdue University 1954. Career at JWT: Mailroom, Detroit Office 1954; New York Office 1955; Vice President 1965; Senior Vice President 1972; Manager, New York Advertising 1974; Executive Vice President 1975; General Manager, Detroit Office 1975. Left JWT for N.W. Ayer 1977. Died 1999.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. George Eversman papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company Archives collections held in the Hartman Center: New York Office Records; International Offices; London Office Records; Frankfurt Office Records.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1973-1976 and includes memoranda, research and status reports and other printed materials. Materials document Eversman's tenure as Manager of New York Advertising. Subsidiaries represented include JWT Europe as well as the London and Frankfurt offices. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company
- George Eversman Papers, 1973-1976 and undated; 1
  - Advertising planning process, 1974 (Box 1)
  - "Close-Up" session, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Communication plan, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Corporate communications planning, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Don Johnston, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - International, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - JWT Europe--Company charts, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - JWT Europe--Minutes, 1975 (Box 1)
  - JWT Europe--New Business Report, 1975 (Box 1)
  - London Office--I-Group Network Charts, 1975 (Box 1)
  - London Office--Planning Guide, 1974 (Box 1)
  - London Office--Some Observations on Forecasting and Planning, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Management Group--World Highlights, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Media Department, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - New business, 1975 (Box 1)
  - New York Advertising, 1975 (Box 2)
  - New York Advertising--Financial, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - New York Management Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Operating Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Research Department, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Some Observations on NYA (New York Advertising), 1975 (Box 2)
  - Study of the Reputation J. Walter Thompson (Louis Harris), 1974 (Box 2)
  - T-Plan, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Target planning/T-Plan, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Telecommunications/JWT Dialog, 1975 (Box 2)
  - "Undercover Admen: JWT Linked to CIA Front (Advertising Age), 1975 (Box 2)
  - Unit System/Frankfurt, 1975 (Box 2)